Guide to the Violet Hunt papers, 1858-1962.
Hunt, Violet papers, 1858-1962.
- Series II. Correspondence
  - 6. By and to others (by author, then by date)
    - Coghill, Nevill, 1899- -- [1917-1918] (Box 9, Folder 35)
      Athlone, Ireland Dear Miss Dodd Mother sent your letter/on
    - Deverell, Wykeham -- Feb. 18, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      AL [copy] S to Frederic George Stephenus
      City Liberal Club, Walbrook, E.C. Dear Stephenus I was glad to see in/the Times
      Wykeham Deverell was Walter Howell Deverell's brother.
    - Divckbank, William -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 37)
      AL [frag.] S to [?]
      [n.p.] ...left quarter...both appear
      With fragment of a drawing on the verso.
    - Eastlake, Charles Lock, Sir, 1793-1865. -- Dec. 16, 1854 (Box 9, Folder 38)
      ALS to Alfred Edward Chalon
      7 Fitzroy Sq. My dear Sir Your academic friends/have all
    - Fogg-Elliot, Amerye Margaret -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 39)
      ALS to Rosamund Fogg-Elliot Wilkinson
      Elvet Hill, Durham My dear Rosamond Where is Mammy/Baby is a bad
    - Gaskell, Elizabeth Cleghorn, 1810-1865. -- June 26 [n.y.] (Box 9, Folder 40)
      ALS to Dora Greenwell
    - Gaskell, Elizabeth Cleghorn, 1810-1865 (continued) -- June 26 [n.y.] (Box 9, Folder 40)
      Plymouth Grove My dear Miss Greenwell I am afraid I/am not a very good person
    - Grant, Francis, Sir, 1803-1878. -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 41-a)
      [n.p.] ...my picture of the Duke/very
      With sketch by Grant in the letter and response by [?] written at the end of the letter.
    - Grant, Francis, Sir, 1803-1878. -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 41-b)
      [n.p.] ...my visit wont be half so/jolly
      With sketch by Grant in the letter.
    - Hale, William Hale, 1795-1870. -- Apr. 1850 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      AL [copy] to Mr. Brockedon
      Charterhouse Dear - (Mr Brockedon) You lately urged me to reduce into order
      10 ll.
      With copy of paper enclosed in the letter.
    - Hamilton, John D. -- Apr. 18, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 43)
      TL [copy] to Stewart Marsh Ellis
      Glasgow Dear Sir The anecdote of Lord Westbury and Tessy
      With another letter from Hamilton to Ellis, dated April 24, 1926. Stewart Marsh Ellis was the author of Mainly Victorian (London, 1925), mentioned in the letters.
    - La Fevriere, Maude -- Nov. 11 [1925] (Box 9, Folder 44-a)
      Walford, Ross on Wye Dear Miss Dodd Your kind &/sympathetic letter has
      2 ll. + 2.
      The photograph of unidentified woman which was enclosed with the letter is now housed in Box 19, Folder 10.
    - [M.] -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 44-b)
      ALS [init.] to Howard
      [n.p.] Dearest H. Many thanks, so glad you're resting.
    - Marzials, Theophilus, 1850-1920 -- 1879-1883, [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 45-a-j)
      Typed copies of letters and fragments of letters to [Cyril Davenport?]
      15 ll. + 1
      With folder which originally housed these typescripts and other material Violet Hunt was collecting.
    - Morris, William, 1834-1896. -- Jan. 10, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 46)
      ALS to ?
      Kelmscott House, Hammersmith Dear Sir I should think that/our carpet room
    - Mueller, Sophus -- Nov. 30, 1871 (Box 9, Folder 47)
      Dublin Dear Sir You ask me, if I know anything
    - Pollock, Walter Herries, 1850-1926. -- Apr. 6, 1894 (Box 9, Folder 48-a-b)
      ALS to [M?] Coutts
      South Lodge Dear [M?] Coutts I am so glad you/liked the article.
      With brief biography of Pollock.
    - [Ponsonby?], Henry -- Apr. 5, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 49)
      ALS to W.G. Cusins
      Cannes Dear Sir The Queen will/be happy to accept
      Concerns the dedication of Francis Hueffer's work on "The Half Century of Music in England."
    - Rimmer, Thomas -- Oct. 30, 1859 (Box 9, Folder 50)
      ALS to William [Rimmer?]
      Montreal My dear Will It is a long time since anything
    - Ronge, Johannes -- June 27, 1857 (Box 9, Folder 51)
      ALS to Latitia Scott
      Birmingham Dear friend, Since I have not written to you it is a long time past.
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- May 30, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 52-a)
      TL [copy] to Albert Fleming
      Waterhead My dear Fleming I, know you would do all you could for me
      With another typed copy containing notes by Violet Hunt and a handwritten copy made by Margaret Hunt.
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 4, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 52-b)
      Kate Raven's Dear Fleming It is entirely wonderful and dreadful
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 6, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 52-c)
      Kate Raven's Dearest Albert, I have had as much comfort from your letter
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 20, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 52-d)
      Brantwood, Coniston Dearest Albert, I send you the first notes for preface and title page
      With handwritten copy made by Margaret Hunt.
    - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 52-e)
      AL [copy] to Miss Folly
      [n.p.] My dear Madam I am obliged to you for your
      In Margaret Hunt's hand.
    - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- June 15, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 53)
      ALS to Horace Harrall
      Ayrshire My Dear Harrall I told the clerk/at the Newcastle Chronicle
    - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. (continued) -- June 15, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Simpson, W. Sparrow (William Sparrow), 1828-1897. -- Nov. 28, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 54-a)
      ALS to George J. Murray
      9, Amen Court, E.C. Dear Sir I will bear in mind
    - Simpson, W. Sparrow (William Sparrow), 1828-1897. -- Nov. 30, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 54-b)
      9, Amen Court, E.C. My dear Sir Here are the Gazettes.
    - Smith, Sydney -- Oct. 26, 1843 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      56 Greer St. My dear Sir I am very glad you approve
    - South London Fine Art Gallery, Reading Room and Lecture Hall -- Aug. 2, 1899 (Box 9, Folder 56)
      ALS to Frederic Shields
      South London Dear Sir Thank you for your letter. I hope
      Written and signed by W[illiam] Rossiter.
    - Stephens, Frederick George, 1828-1907. -- Feb. 17, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 57)
      L [Printed] S to [Walter Howell] Deverell
      9, Hammersmith Terrace, W. Dear Deverell In his recently published autobiography Mr. Holman Hunt
    - Swinburne, Edward -- May 31, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 58)
      ALS to Theodore Watts
      20 Ennismore Gardens Dear Watts, My Mother has shown me the letter from/Longbourne
    - W., R. -- Apr. 2, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 59)
      ALS [init.] to Annie Child
      3 Elm Ct. Dear Child, I shall come along
    - W., R. (continued) -- Apr. 2, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 59)
      With note on verso by Violet Hunt and with another leaf with note in an unidentified hand.
      Annie Child was Violet Hunt's maid.
    - Wilkinson, Rosamund Fogg-Elliot -- [n.d.] (Box 9, Folder 60-a)
      ALS to Amerye Fogg-Elliot
      Ilkley, Yorkshire My dearest Amerye. That is the nicest/letter
    - Wilkinson, Rosamund Fogg-Elliot -- Oct. 26, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 60-b)
      Ilkley, Yorkshire My dearest Amerye, I did/enjoy my walk with Aunt Violet
  - 7. Violet Hunt's Estate
    - Allen, C. H. G. -- Sept. 11, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 1-a-d)
      ALS to Gerald Henderson
      St. Albans, Herts. Dear Sir I am writing to you as I/understand you
      With TM [ draft] of Henderson's response, dated September 27, 1948, and AMS [ init.] of Henderson's response, dated September 28, 1948.
      Concerns the use of Violet's Howell material.
    - Atlantic Monthly Press -- Mar. 2, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      TLS to Gerald Henderson
      Boston My dear Mr. Hudson: We understand that you
      Signed by Stanley Salmen.
    - Cecil Houses -- May 1939 (Box 10, Folder 3-a-b)
      London Dear Mr. Henderson, Proposed Memorial to Lady Ottline Morrell
    - Cecil Houses (continued) -- May 1939 (Box 10, Folder 3-a-b)
      Signed by Lady Laura Lovet and Mrs. Cecil Chesterton.
      With a printed sheet about Cecil Houses.
    - Cochrane, Irene -- Sept. 15, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      ALS to Mabel Cole
      10, Pembridge Place, W.2. My dear Cole, It must be at least 24 years since I met/"Beatrice Ellen" Allen
      Signed "Cockie."
    - Dahl, Curtis -- Oct. 24, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Knoxville, Tennessee Dear Sir: Through the kindness of Constable/and Company
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd. -- Mar. 27, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6-a)
      Strand, London Dear Mr. Henderson, I am anxious to include at any rate one novel by Violet
      Signed by Graham Greene.
      With envelope and advertisement for The Century Library.
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd. -- Apr. 17, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6-b)
      Strand, London Dear Mr. Henderson, Many thanks for your letter.
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd. -- Apr. 24, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6-c)
      Strand, London Dear Mr. Henderson, I enclose our contracts for "WHITE ROSE OF WEARY/LEAF".
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd. (continued) -- Apr. 24, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6-c)
      One copy of the contracts mentioned in this letter is housed with the letter from May 9, 1946.
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd. -- May 9, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 6-d)
      Strand, London Dear Mr. Henderson, We have altered the contract
      With contract for republication of White Rose of Weary Leaf, dated April 23, 1946.
    - Eyre & Spottiswoode Ltd. -- [June 7, 1946] (Box 10, Folder 6-e)
      AN [ printed] [re royalty advance]
      London With the Compliments to Eyre & Spottiswoode
    - Farrar Porter & Co. (Solicitors) -- Oct. 23, 1942-January 23, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 7-a-m)
      13 TLS to Gerald Henderson
      20 ll.
      With two envelopes, one account statement, and typed copies of five letters between Farrar Porter and Richardson Sadler.
    - Farrar Porter & Co. (Solicitors) -- Apr. 5, 1944-June 19, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 8-a-c)
      3 TLS to Mabel Henderson
      3 ll. + 2
      With Violet Hunt, TD, [account of surplus income], 1949-1952.
    - Fleet Publishing Company (New York) -- May 8 and 25, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 9-a-b)
      2 TLS to Gerald Henderson
      Signed by Marcia Prince, Assistant Editor.
      With Gerald Henderson's response written on the front of the letter of May 8.
      With one envelope.
    - Goldring, Douglas, 1887- -- Sept. 22, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10-a)
      TL to Gerald Henderson
      Kingsley, Bordon, Hants Dear Mr. Henderson, My book, "South Lodge" is now nearing
    - Goldring, Douglas, 1887- -- Jan. 22, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 10-b)
      Kingsley, Bordon, Hants Dear Mr. Henderson, As I have not had a reply
      With a draft of Henderson's response, dated January 27, 1943, written on the letter in pencil.
    - Grant, W. -- Aug. 10 and 30, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 11-a-b)
      2 ALS to Gerald Henderson
      With both envelopes.
      Concerns the use of Violet Hunt's Howell material.
    - Henderson, Gerald William, 1889-1962. -- [Jan. 28, 1942] (Box 10, Folder 12)
      TL [ copy] to Richardson Sadler & Co.
      London Dear Sirs, Miss Isabel Violet Hunt dec'd.
      With envelope addressed to Henderson from Richardson Sadler & Co. and postmarked January 26, 1942.
    - Nehls, Edward -- Oct. 21 and December 30, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 13-a-d)
      2 ll. + 7
      With enclosed permission form and draft of Henderson's response to the letter of October 21.
      With two TLS from Arthur Pell of Liveright Publishing Corp. to Gerald Henderson, dated January 9 and July 10, 1956.
      With three envelopes.
    - The Worthing Art Development Scheme -- Feb. 1-22, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 14-a-e)
      4 TLS to Douglas Goldring
      4 ll. + 3
      Signed by W. Hy. Odell.
      With a note from Goldring to Gerald Henderson on the bottom of the letter of February 1 and with a draft of Henderson's response to the letter dated February 6, 1945.
      With two envelopes.
    - Partington, Wilfred -- Oct. 24, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      Wimbledon Dear Sir, I hope you will excuse the intrusion/of this letter
    - Richardson Sadler & Co. (solicitors) -- Oct. 26, 1943 and March 30, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 16-a-b)
      2 TL [ copy] to Farrar Porter & Co.
    - Richardson Sadler & Co. (solicitors) -- Jan. 29 and February 4, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 16-c-d)
    - Rupert Hart-Davis Limited -- Apr. 14, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      London Dear Mr Henderson, Somebody told me that you have control
    - Henderson, Gerald William, 1889-1962. -- Apr. 8, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      D [Passport]
      British passport.
    - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- July 23, 1947-October 8, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      TD [estate account]
    - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- Sept. 11, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      TD [estate agreement]
    - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- Feb. 29-November 22, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      TD [ copy] [estate capital and income accounts]
      With envelope addressed to Gerald Henderson.
    - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- Oct. 16, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      TD [ copy] Will
- Series III. Diaries
  - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- 1876 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    AM Diary for 1876
    26 ll. + 1
    Bound volume with almanack for 1876 printed on front.
  - Hunt, Margaret Raine, 1831-1912. -- Nov. 17, 1882 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    AM Diary fragment
  - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- 1895-1903 (Box 10, Folder 25-a-m)
    TM Diary extracts 1887-88, 1892,
    95 ll. + 1
    With cover of file previously housing these pages.
    On verso of most pages are unidentified fragments of manuscripts, including some possibly by Ford Madox Ford.
  - Hunt, Violet, 1862-1942. -- Jan. 1-July 25, 1890 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    AM Diary for 1890
    94 ll. + 1
    Bound volume with black cover.
  - AM Diary for 1890-1891 -- July 27, 1890-May 3, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    101 ll. + 1
  - TM Diary for 1891 -- 1891 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    250 ll. + 1
  - TM Diary for January 24-30, 1891 -- Jan. 24-30, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Two copies, original and carbon, of both pages.
    With note explaining that this is different from the typed 1891 diary, which corresponds to events in the manuscript diary.
  - AM Diary for 1891 -- May 5-November 20, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    92 ll. + 1
  - TM Diary for August 22-31, 1891 -- Aug. 22-31, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    7 ll. + 1
    Two copies, original and carbon, of three of the four pages.
  - TM Diary for August 22-31, 1891 (continued) -- Aug. 22-31, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - TM Diary for September 15-30, 1891 -- Sept. 15-30, 1891 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    20 ll. + 1
    Two copies, original and carbon.
  - TM Diary for 1892--[bound version] -- 1892 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    157 ll. + 1
    Diary disbound.
    With cover, with notes by Violet.
  - TM Diary for 1892 -- Sept.-December 1892 (Box 11, Folder 8-a-l)
    64 ll. + 1
    With note stating that this typed material corresponds to events in the bound 1892 diary; the variants appear to be an earlier, shorter version.
    Both original and carbon of many pages.
  - TM Diary for 1893 -- 1893 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    83 ll.
  - AM Diary for 1893-1894 -- Feb. 5, 1893-July 1894 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    61 ll. + 1
  - AM Diary for 1894-1896 -- July 9, 1894-April 28, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    63 ll.
  - TM Diary for 1895 -- 1895 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    60 ll.
  - TM Diary extracts -- 1895-1909 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Concerning Violet's mother, Margaret Raine.
  - AM Diary for 1896-1897 -- Apr. 29, 1896-December 9, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    62 ll. + 1
  - AM Diary for 1897-1900 -- Dec. 9, 1897-September 1900 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    89 ll. + 10 + 1
    With sent and unsent letters to Oswald Crawfurd, some loose and some pasted in,
  - AM Diary for 1897-1900 (continued) -- Dec. 9, 1897-September 1900 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    towards the end of the volume.
  - TM Diary for 1907 -- 1907 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    104 ll.
  - AM Diary for 1917 -- 1917 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    36 ll. + 1
    Bound volume with green paper cover.
    No entries until August; most quite brief.
  - AM Diary for 1935-1939 -- 1935-1939 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    150 ll. + 1
    Bound volume with tan buckram cover.
  - TM & AM Diary entry -- Sept. 28, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Diary 2ts. carbon -- 1901 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Diary ms. excerpts -- 1901 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Diary -- 1902 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Diary -- Jan. 1, 1931-Aug. 31, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Hunt Violent -- 1914 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Diary/account/record book
  - Hunt Violent -- 1918 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Hunt Violent -- 1919 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Manuscripts
  - 1. By Violet Hunt
    - a. Literary and General
      - AM [accounts, recipes, lists, etc.] -- [1879-1880] (Box 12, Folder 10)
        73 ll. + 1
        Volume with white vellum cover and clasp.
      - AM Address book -- [after 1909] (Box 12, Folder 11)
        82 ll. + 1
        With stamp of Ford Madox Ford,"FMH," on second leaf.
        With annotations and commentary.
        Volume with deep red leather cover.
      - TM Walks With Andrew Lang -- [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 12)
        With annotations in Violet Hunt's hand. Mentions the sale of Dante Gabriel Rossetti's estate.
        With original folder.
      - AM Poems, "How long, how long--..." in Violet Hunt's hand; AM, three poems in unidentified hand: "The slight skiff sails...," "In Spring whan all the sweet birds sing,..." and "Her poor arms lay streaked..."; -- [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 13-a-c)
      - AM [by Ford Madox Ford?] -- [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 14)
        In three cases he simply refutes with slight elaboration what I have [?]/ in my memoir without any correction other
        References to the Bicknell family.
        Written in pencil; not in Hunt's hand.
      - [Hunt, Violet?] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 1)
        TM & AM The Assistant Professor
        22 ll.
        Attributed to "Ramon Perez de Ayala" on the title page.
        With many handwritten annotations.
      - AM Bankbook -- 1912-1920 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        30 ll. + 1
        London County & Westminster Bank, Ltd.
        Volume with white vellum cover; "Mrs. I.V. Hueffer" written on cover.
      - TM & AM Baths -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 3)
        On verso of fragment of manuscript of The Wife of Rossetti (p. 85).
      - AM & TM [genealogy of Bethell family] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 4)
        Violet was trying to show the relationship between her nurse, Emma Brown, and the Bethell family.
      - AM & TM [bits and pieces] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 5)
        torn bits of paper + 1
      - TM [book review - draft] -- [193?] (Box 13, Folder 6)
        Review of book by Hugh Kingsmill?
        On stationery of CLOSE UP: An International Review devoted to the art of films.
      - TM [book reviews] -- [1935-1936] (Box 13, Folder 7-a-h)
        15 ll.
        Some with early drafts. Books reviewed are J.D. Mackie's Cavalier and Puritan, Olaf Stapleton's Odd John, E.M. Forster's Abinger
      - TM [book reviews] (continued) -- [1935-1936] (Box 13, Folder 7-a-h)
        Some with early drafts. Books reviewed are Harvest, Hugh Kingsmill's What They Said at the Time, Grand Tour (edited by R.S. Lambert), Malcolm Letts's As the Foreigner Saw Us, C.M. Franzero's Roman Britain, and Gretchen Green's The Whole World and Company.
      - Envelopes -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 8-a-k)
        11 ll.
        With notes written in Violet Hunt's hand on the envelopes.
      - AM Extract Book -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 9)
        51 ll. + 1
        Extracts from works by different authors.
        Volume with marbled paper cover; "Extract Book/Violet " written on a piece of paper attached to the front cover.
      - TM [instructions for household maintenance] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - AM List of letters -- [after 1925] (Box 13, Folder 11)
        50 ll. + 1
        In blue check notebook.
        The letters are from between 1847 and 1925.
        Many of the letters noted here are to Alfred, Margaret, and Violet, though some are to Ford Madox Ford and his family, and others are to unrelated individuals.
      - AM [frag.] Mabel's Playmates. or Pigeon Jack. -- July 19, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 12)
        14 ll. + 1
        Bound volume with red, yellow, and black marbled cover.
      - AM Not Invited ! or Miss Bertram's Mistake -- June 23, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 13)
        10 ll. + 1 + 3
        Title on title page differs slightly.
        Bound volume with green cover. With two sheets of blank paper from the "Fleece Hotel, Darlington" and Ezra Pound's calling card, with annotations by Pound and notes by Violet, tucked inside.
      - AM [ fragmentary notes on the division of her belongings and literary projects for her will] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - AM [notes on Orsini] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 15)
        9 ll.
      - TM & AM [notes on various subjects] -- [ca. 1935] (Box 13, Folder 16-a-gg)
        61 ll. + 3
        Notes on newspaper clippings, Charles Augustus Howell, Ford Madox Ford, Alfred William Hunt's sketches, Edward Burne-Jones, Thomas Hardy, John Ruskin, Violet's life and estate, and D.H. Lawrence, among others.
        Many on verso of pages from other manuscripts, including The Wife of Rossetti.
        With three pages of photocopies of the newspaper clippings.
      - AM The Painful Origins of V. H. -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 17)
        Includes photocopy of same.
      - AM Parting at Sunset--[poem] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 18)
        In Violet Hunt's hand, though unclear whether it is by her.
      - AM Poetry -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 19)
        47 ll. + 1
        Handwritten copies of poems by many different poets.
        Volume with marbled paper covers; "Poetry/V. Hunt" written on a piece of paper attached to front cover.
      - AM Social Addresses -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 20)
        122 ll. + 1
      - TM [South Lodge inventory] -- [n.d.] (Box 13, Folder 21)
        32 ll. + 1
      - TM & AM Tor Villa -- [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 1-a-f)
        109 ll + 1
        With folder cover containing the title "Tor Villa" and Violet Hunt's notes. The title on the inside is "The Passion for Romance."
      - TM & AM Tor Villa (continued) -- [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 1-a-f)
        Hunt's reminiscences of life at Tor Villa, including excerpts on Oscar Wilde, Theo Marzials, William Bell Scott, G. P. Boyce, Swinburne, Holman Hunt, Edward Burne Jones, and others.
      - AM & TM "Wanted for Attempt" -- [notes] -- [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 2-a-bb & 3-a-u)
        354 ll. + 1
        Concerning Orsini, probably part of Hunt's Howell material.
        Much of the material consists of bits of paper which were attached to sheets of paper.
        Housed in two folders (192 ll. + 162 ll.), with original cover with notes made by Violet Hunt.
        On verso of some sheets are typed manuscript pages from Hunt's autobiography, The Flurried Years, while on the verso of many of the bits of paper are unidentified fragments.
        Includes a numbered index [typed].
      - TM & AM The War -- [n.d.] (Box 14, Folder 4)
        On verso of a fragment of another unidentified manuscript, possibly by Ford Madox Ford.
      - "Euphemia II (Ruskin)" -- Oct. 1860-May 1864 69 (Box 25, Folder 1)
        [+] pp.
      - "Euphemia III (Millais: Eastlakes) -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 2)
        76pp.; 22pp.
      - "Dolores III" (Swinburne) -- 1870-End (Box 25, Folder 3)
        assorted pages; 93[+]pp.
      - "Gooseberry" -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 4)
        galley proofs with annotations
      - "Rossetti's Saynete" -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 5)
        ts. 3pp. with annotations
      - "Library" [of Violet Hunt] -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 6)
        galley proof
      - "Record of Visitors" -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - [Family Chronology] -- 1840-1911 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - "A double Performance" -- 1902 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - "Stronger than Love" -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - "The End of the Beginning" -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - "Ruskin as a Guide to Youth" -- [n.d.] (Box 25, Folder 12)
        clipping, photocopy